The weather affects all of us.
天气影响我们所有人。
An unexpected downpour or hot spell can be annoying, but when conditions are more extreme, it can severely impact agriculture, transport infrastructure and our homes.
一场突如其来的暴雨或是一段持续高温天气可能会让人烦躁，但当天气状况变得更加极端时，就会严重影响农业生产、交通基础设施以及我们的住房。
It's no surprise that for centuries scientists have tried to control the weather – but is it really possible?
毫不出奇，科学家们几个世纪以来一直在尝试控制天气——但这真的能实现吗？
Due to climate change, there are more regular occurrences of heatwaves, which cause droughts, and torrential rain, which is responsible for flooding.
由于气候变化的缘故，热浪和暴雨的出现愈发频繁，前者会引发干旱，后者则会导致洪水。
Although humans are the cause of much of it, maybe we have a solution too?
尽管这在很大程度上是人类活动造成的，但或许我们也能找到解决办法？
For example, China, the UAE and the USA are at the forefront of research into methods of producing rain in drought-stricken areas.
例如，中国、阿联酋和美国在干旱地区人工降雨方法的研究领域处于领先地位。
And some scientists are even thinking about investigating technologies which could cool the entire planet.
一些科学家甚至在考虑研发能够给整个地球降温的技术。
It might sound like science fiction, but weather modification is nothing new.
这听起来或许像科幻小说里的情节，但气象调节并不是什么新鲜事。
In the 1940s, scientists discovered that dropping particles of silver iodide into cloud tops, made the tiny water droplets condense and could stimulate precipitation.
20世纪40年代，科学家们发现，将碘化银颗粒撒入云层顶部，能够促使微小的水滴凝结，进而形成降水。
That's called cloud seeding.
这种方法被称为人工增雨。
This is a technique still being tested today with the aim of producing extra rainfall and, therefore, water for drought-affected farmers.
如今这项技术仍在试验阶段，其目的是增加降雨量，从而为受干旱影响的农民提供水源。
Other ideas for keeping nature at bay include using lasers to generate clouds and for controlling thunderstorms.
其他抵御极端天气的构想还包括利用激光造云以及控制雷暴。
One idea involved firing laser pulses into thunderclouds in an attempt to suck out lightning in a controlled manner. This was unsuccessful.
有一个构想是向雷雨云发射激光脉冲，试图以可控的方式引导闪电释放，但这个尝试并未成功。
New research into solar geoengineering has also begun. This type of climate engineering involves sunlight being reflected back to space to limit or reverse human-caused climate change.
太阳能地球工程的相关研究也已启动，这类气候工程技术旨在将太阳光反射回太空，从而限制或逆转人类活动引发的气候变化。
Despite all this ongoing research, there's no conclusive evidence that our weather can be controlled.
尽管相关研究一直在进行，但目前尚无确凿证据表明人类能够控制天气。
Chris Bell, a lecturer in meteorology at the University of East Anglia, told BBC Future: "We may, one day, have the technology to control the weather, but it will be in thousands, not hundreds, of years."
东安格利亚大学的气象学讲师克里斯·贝尔在接受BBC未来频道采访时表示：“或许有一天，我们会掌握控制天气的技术，但这需要数千年的时间，而非几百年。”
So, for now, we still need to rely on Mother Nature to control our weather.
因此，目前仍然是大自然掌控天气。